♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we've got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we'll withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko stronger after all ♪
So you’re saying that this thing could destroy someone who’s under Xana’s control?
It isn’t a thing, it’s an EMP bomb.
It makes an electromagnetic explosion
that affects anything electronic.
And because the pixelated body of someone
under Xana’s control is held together by a forcefield, well.
Ah, Jeremie, we’ve got a class in twenty minutes,
can you give us the cliffsnotes version?
(LAUGHING)
Bomb explodes,
guy under Xana’s control obliterated.
Great.
Right, except for one little thing.
We haven’t come up with a mini version yet.
(BELL RINGING)
Huh, what do you know,
Yumi isn’t here with you.
Oh, of course not, I just saw her with William,
how stupid of me!
You got that right.
Hmph.
Why is it whenever you see Sissi,
you feel like being nasty?
Maybe because being with someone nasty rubs off on you.
An activated tower!
XANA’s on the move again!
Too bad for our music class.
Let’s get to the factory.
Where do you think you kids are going?
That’s the way to your classroom.
Oh no.
Well, I’ve gotta get to music class with the others.
Lucky you, we’ve got chemistry.
Ah! Visual on the principal.
Good morning, Mr. Delmas, we were just on our way to class--
Hey! That hurts!
What’s the matter with you, sir?
You can’t treat students that way!
Wait! What are you doing?
Help!
Let go of me, sir, you’re hurting me!
Hey, stop!
Hey! Yumi!
William!
Help! The principal’s gone totally crazy!
He’s kidnapped Yumi and Odd!
(PLAYING MUSIC)
Delmas has just kidnapped Ishiyama and Della Robbia!
XANA!
What kind of nonsense is this?
But it’s true, sir! He even beat up William Dunbar!
Don’t you move, I’ll be right back.
It’s incredible.
Yumi isn’t answering, and Odd isn’t either.
A message from XANA.
“Aelita at two o’clock in the Ice Sector to give herself up to
the Scyphozoa. If not, Odd and Yumi will be liquidated.”
(GASP)
We don’t have any time to lose, let’s go!
Okay!
I want everybody in their seats right now.
How do people expect us to save the world
if they don’t leave us alone.
And quiet down!
Where are we?
Given the temperature,
I would g-g-guess somewhere north of Siberia.
My cell phone!
He must’ve taken them from us!
We’ve gotta get out of here,
before we freeze to death!
Uh… Mr. Delmas, sir?
Odd, are you okay?
Yeah, sure I am,
but I wouldn’t count on his cooperating with us.
Right then. Everybody here?
Classes are cancelled for the rest of the day,
you can all go home.
Sissi and William,
the detective would like to ask you a few questions.
Hey, what about those guys? You should question them, too,
they’re always scheming with Odd and Yumi!
Stern, Belpois, and Stones!
Definitely not our day.
I wouldn’t be surprised if they knew something about what happened to my father!
Come on, you three. Follow me.
Ready?
Go!
What? Hey, come on, get back here!
We got her!
I’ll handle this!
(SHIVERING)
My f-friend is really cold!
Hey! XANA! Apparently you plan on keeping us alive,
or you’d have already blown us away.
Uh, in case you didn’t know, cold can kill us too,
so if I were you, I’d do something about it!
Nice going, Sissi.
You really messed up this time.
It so happens that we’re the only ones that can help your father.
What do you mean?
Your father is, uh… p-possessed.
Oh yeah, right.
Like in Hospital of Horrors?
And he’s been taken over by a demonic entity
that can make him do unspeakable things, huh?
Well, basically, that’s about it.
Huh?
Yumi, are you okay?
Where are you?
If you ask me, we’re at the refrigerated warehouses
on the wharf just-- hey!
Huh?
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Yumi? Yumi!
So, in order to help my father,
you have to go and deactivate a tower that’s in a virtual universe?
That’s right.
My last question…
Why should I help a couple of completely wacko pathological liars, huh?
Keep it down!
It’s not us you’ll be helping, it’s your father!
You have to trust us, I’m begging you!
Thank you, you can go home now.
Elisabeth Delmas, it’s your turn.
Jeremie, next time,
leave me an instruction manual.
Yes!
It’s true that my father’s
been acting kinda weird for a while now.
He’s taken to locking himself in the basement to
tinker around, and he says strange things, too.
The other day, he told me he was fed up with life.
I told him that it was only natural for a school principal
with such a heavy load to feel that way.
And then he started laughing in a really crazy way
And said he did have a heavy load but he hadn’t decided where to set it off yet.
And then, I also heard him on the phone saying he’d gotten some material,
I didn’t really get what he said, it sounded like…
Decorators or destinators or…
Detonators?
Yeah, that was it!
Evacuate the school!
Huh?
Thanks for trusting us, Sissi.
Don’t mention it.
But, if your story about a virtual world turns out to be phony, you’re gonna regret it!
Ulrich, where are you?
On my way to the refrigerated warehouses,
I’m gonna try to set Yumi and Odd free.
XANA’s ultimatum expires in fifteen minutes!
I’ll go as fast as I can.
Meet you at the factory!
Sissi, what are you doing?
I’m coming with you!
Remember, my father’s involved in this.
And I wanna check out all this virtual world business
you’ve been blabbering about!
Oh, alright!
Wow, I feel like I’m in a James Bond movie!
XANA doesn’t waste time.
Your friend, the Scyphozoa,
is already waiting for you.
How much time before the ultimatum is up?
Two minutes.
Hurry! One minute to go, Ulrich!
But Jeremie, there are dozens of cold rooms here!
I should’ve handed myself over to the Scyphozoa.
No, Ulrich’s gonna make it!
The ultimatum is up!
(SCREAMING)
Odd!
No, Mr. Delmas, stop!
(SCREAMING)
Jeremie, that bomb you made,
it won’t blow away the principal, will it?
Uh, well, theoretically speaking, no.
Watch out!
Ulrich! Ulrich, can you hear me?
You said that that bomb fried anything electronic,
so that would mean cell phones too, right?
Oh, I’m such a dork!
I hadn’t thought of that!
Can we find out if it worked?
My father might be dead by now.
Or in great shape,
giving Odd and Yumi a piece of his mind.
It worked!
Yeah, but it wrecked my mobile.
Ugh… what’s going on?
I’ll explain on the way!
Come on, let’s get to the factory!
Oh no, what rotten luck!
Uh, Jeremie.
Nice job!
Where’d you learn to punch like that?
I took Pencak Silat classes,
to impress Ulrich, but it didn’t work.
By the way, why did you ask me to do that?
I have to help Ulrich, Odd, and Yumi.
Only I can deactivate the tower,
and Jeremie would have never let me do it.
Sissi, now!
Are you, uhm… are you sure?
Yes, Sissi! Do it!
Get to the factory, I’ll take care of him!
Jeremie? Uh, Jeremie, uh,
I think there’s a problem.
Ugh… oh, my head…
Well, Aelita is there, in… in the video game, and there’s some kind of giant squid.
Huh, what?
Oh no! Aelita, are you crazy?
To Lyoko, fast!
What about my father?
Is he alright?
Couldn’t be better.
He’s outside, playing with Ulrich.
Aelita’s on the plateau, ahead of you.
Take the tunnel, I’ll keep going straight.
Read you loud and clear, chief!
Hurry up!
Will you be alright?
Uh-huh.
Ok, saddle up.
The activated tower should be straight ahead of you.
Watch it now.
Move it! Ulrich must be taking a beating up there!
Sissi-- uh, Sissi?
Jeremie, there’s no activated tower here!
The scan picked it up,
it has to be somewhere!
Your pals, the Tarantulas, are there!
Thanks for the tip!
Look!
It looks like the entrance to an ice cave!
Banzai!
Ulrich, are you okay?
Daddy, no!
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Leave him alone!
Odd, you get one of those Tarantulas,
and I’ll handle the other one!
Okay!
Aelita, you’re gonna have to jump at the right moment.
Hurry, Ulrich’s getting massacred,
and so is Sissi now!
(SCREAMING)
Laser arrow!
Shield!
Change of plan,
you take the controls!
Let’s go!
Now!
Here’s the tower!
Hurry up!
(CELESTIAL MUSIC)
Daddy!
(SCREAMING)
Tower deactivated.
Ulrich, are you alright?
Yeah, thanks to you.
Thanks a lot, Sissi.
He… is he…?
No, just knocked out. Don’t worry.
What’s going to happen to him now?
I mean, with the kidnapping and everything.
Everything’s gonna be alright,
no one will remember anything.
Neither will you, for that matter.
And you?
I will. For me, it’s not the same.
Okay, then you’ll remember this kiss.
You can go ahead, Einstein.
I wonder which would be worse,
being blind or having to see this.
See what?
Return to the past now!
Huh, what do you know,
Yumi isn’t here with you.
Oh, of course not,
I just saw her with William, how stupid of me!
Ciao!
Uh, Ulrich, hello?
You still thinking about what happened on the bridge?
What happened on the bridge?
Yeah, what did happen on the bridge?
Nothing.
Odd?
But it’s true, nothing happened.
Okay, it’s time for class.
Something smells really fishy…
What could they be hiding?
Don’t worry,
I’m sure it’s just another boy thing.
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY THE FOXTROT FANATICS